Emma Reid

Contact

emma.chia.reid@gmail.com 737-226-4537 linkedin.com/in/emma-chia-reid emmareid.design

Tools

Sketch
Adobe XD
Visual Studio Code
HTML, CSS, Javascript
Github
InVision Studio

Skills

Research:

User Interviews/Surveys
Card-Sorting
Ethnographic Observations
Affinity Diagrams
Information Architecture
Heuristic Evaluation
User Flows
SWOT Analysis
Moodboards
Site Maps
Persona
User Journey Mapping
Storyboard

Design:

Interface Design
Wireframing
Low to Hi-fi Prototyping
Front-end Development

Soft Skills:

Collaborative
Creative
Detail Oriented
Effective Communicator
Empathetic
Inquisitive

About

A UX/UI designer with a passion for improving people's lives through design thinking. Using my empathetic nature, I create human centered, intuitive design to remove friction between user's actions and their goals.

Projects | Portfolio

Responsive Design | DELL GAMING SUBSITE

5 week design challenge of research, design, and developing a VR gaming subsite for Dell. Owned mobile design and front-end development of the site.

Responsive Redesign | SAVE AN ANGEL WEBSITE

4 week design challenge of research and redesigning Save an Angel's website to be more responsive and intuitive. Worked closely with stakeholder to meet their needs, and their users' needs. Acted as PM and main designer.

Experience

UX Research Recruiter, Incentive Processor | Google

May 2018 - June 2019 | Austin TX

- Designed new template for customer-facing emails
- Collaborated with UX Researchers for participant recruitment.
- Created UX Research study surveys.
- Expert in study incentivization and conducted office hours for all of Google's UX Operations.

Japanese Data Analyst | Apple

July 2017 - May 2018, Austin TX

- Utilized native Japanese language skills to meet time sensitive deadlines on the live market.
- Created a new manual for the Japanese market for policy consistency.
- Grader for Japanese new hire assessments.

Education

UX/UI Certificate Program | University of Texas

June 2019 - December 2019

Bachelor Japanese Culture & Linguistics | University of Oregon

September 2013 - June 2017, Eugene, OR

Minor in Business Administration.